Guide to the Propaganda Poster Collection 1914-1996
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
- Series 5: French Posters
  - Subseries 5.2: French Post-World War II, 1943-1955
    - Le 6e Arrondissement Adopte Conde-sur-Noireau (Calvados): Campagne "Amitie et Solidarite", 1945; French; 30 x 40 cm. Black and white.; Creator/Publisher: Le Comite de Parrainage. (Folder 82, Item 486)
      Announcement about the campaign of "Amitie et Solidarite" ("Friendship and Solidarity"). Provides a list of significant dates and information about the events.
    - Union des Mouvements de Resistance, 1945; French; 20.5 x 31 cm. Black and white.; Creator/Publisher: Mouvement de Liberation Nationale; Organisation Civile et Militaire; Ceux de la Resistance. (Folder 82, Item 487)
      Provides a list of dates for when the Union des Mouvements de Resistance will hold public meetings before the municipal elections on April 29, 1945.
    - Union des Mouvements de Resistance, 1945; French; 20.5 x 23.5 cm. Black and white.; Creator/Publisher: Mouvement de Liberation Nationale; Organisation Civile et Militaire; Ceux de la Resistance. (Folder 83, Item 488)
      Invitation to the public to attend a grand public meeting on April 23, 1945, prior to the municipal elections.
    - Restrictions d'Electricite: Usagers d'Electricite Attention!, circa 1944-1945; French; 29.5 x 45 cm. Black and white.; Creator/Publisher: La Gutenberg. (Folder 83, Item 489)
      Poster announcing to the public a restriction on electricity. Features a list of penalties and fines.
    - Pour le Secours d'Hiver, circa 1940-1945; French; 32 x 49 cm. Black and white.; Creator/Publisher: L. Hannequin. (Folder 83, Item 490)
      Propaganda poster addressing the people of France and authorized by Roger Langeron, Georges Pichat, and Charles Magny. Includes a quote from Philippe Petain dating from November 1940.
    - [Images of Philippe Petain], circa 1940-1950; French; 34.5 x 55cm. Black and white with red and blue accents.; Creator/Publisher: National Emergency. (Folder 83, Item 491)
      French poster presenting five images of Philippe Petain, each numbered and consisting of a short caption underneath. Lining the two photographs on the far left of the poster, are two stripes, one red, and the other blue.
- Series 6: Miscellaneous, 1914-1990
  - Et Lui? Aidez-nous a Lui Trouver du Travail Quand il Reviendra., circa 1940-1950; French; 52.5 x 82 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: ORAFF. (Folder 83, Item 492)
    Propaganda poster portraying a man, emphasized with his white coloring, depressed facial expression, and empty hands, standing in front of two other men who are colorful and busy working.
  - [World Map], circa 1930-1945; French; 38.5 x 69 cm. Black, white, and blue.; Creator/Publisher: Le Petit Parisien. (Folder 83, Item 493)
    A map of the world printed by Le Petit Parisien, a French newspaper during the French Third Republic.
  - Centennial of the Telegraph: 1844-1944, English; 50.5 x 60.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Unidentified (Folder 84, Item 494)
    Poster illustrating three people surrounding Samuel F.B. Morse as he sends the first telegraph on May 24, 1844.
  - Health, Strength, Joy for All the Children of All the Schools of America, circa 1910-1920; English; 45.5 x 58.5 cm. Black and white.; Creator/Publisher: Government Printing Office. (Folder 84, Item 495)
    A poster distributed by the Department of the Interior Bureau of Education and the Division of School Hygiene to encourage the health of children. Depicts a graphic within an oval border of two children holding hands as they spin around Includes 3 prints
  - [Near East Relief], circa 1914-1918; English; 30.5 x 45.5 cm. Black and white with blue accents.; Creator/Publisher: Unidentified (Folder 84, Item 496)
    Portrays an illustration of a group of starved people with a man holding out his arms to a large cross in the background. Below the image, at the bottom of the poster, are the words, "He gave himself  What will you give.
  - [Four Minute Men], circa 1914-1918; English; 67.5 x 15 cm. Black and white.; Creator/Publisher: Unidentified (Folder 84, Item 497)
    Provides confirmation that the theater was appointed by the US Government to receive messages from the Four Minute Men.
  - Accident Prevention Poster: Get in this Game, circa 1915-1945; English; 21.5 x 28 cm. Black and white.; Creator/Publisher: Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, Department of Labor and Industry. (Folder 85, Item 498)
    Poster with the slogan, "Get in this Game," in order to draw attention to carelessness in the store, shop, and factory that leads to injury and accidents.
  - [Public Statement from George F. Cotterill], 1914; English; 18 x 24 cm. Black and white.; Creator/Publisher: Allied Printing. (Folder 85, Item 499)
    Statement from George F. Cotterill to the citizens of Washington, explaining his intention to file for the Democratic nomination in the United States Senator election of 1914. Includes 3 copies.
  - Mediterranean Cruise, circa 1924-1925; English; 61 x 30.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Unidentified (Folder 85, Item 500)
    Announcement of a cruise ship named the Empress of Scotland to depart from New York for the Mediterranean Sea on February 9, 1925.
  - Exposition Tunisie 45, circa 1945; French; 113.5 x 153 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Bedos and Cie. (Folder 85, Item 501)
    Portrays a graphic on a red backdrop of a large brown hand holding in its palm a building with the Islamic symbol of a star and crescent located behind it.
  - [John Updike Quote], circa 1968-1990; English; 35.5 x 50.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Janus Press. (Folder 85, Item 502)
    Includes an image of a house above a quote from John Updike, an American writer and critic.